Mother. Daughter. Grandmother. In this family,
attitude doesn't skip a generation.
Georgia Rule is a drama, comedy, romance film directed by Garry Marshall.
Rebellious, uncontrollable teenager, Rachel is hauled off by her dysfunctional
mother to spend the summer with her estranged grandmother, Georgia.
Her journey will lead all three women to revelations of buried family secrets and an
understanding that - regardless what happens - the ties that bind can never be broken.
Georgia Randall, played by Jane Fonda.
Rachel Wilcox, played by Lindsay Lohan.
Lilly, played by Felicity Huffman.
Simon Ward, played by Dermot Mulroney.
Arnold, played by Cary Elwes.
Harlan Wilson, played by Garrett Hedlund.
Georgia Rule is a 2007 American comedy-drama film directed by
Garry Marshall and written by Mark Andrus.
It stars Jane Fonda, Lindsay Lohan and Felicity Huffman.
The film follows a rebellious teenager (Lohan) who is sent to spend the summer with her grandmother
(Fonda) when her frustrated mother (Huffman) cannot control her unruly behavior.
Dermot Mulroney, Cary Elwes, Garrett Hedlund, Laurie Metcalf, and
Héctor Elizondo also appear in supporting roles.
Georgia Rule was theatrically released in the United
States on May 11, 2007, by Universal Pictures.
The production of the film came to media attention when a warning
letter from Morgan Creek Productions CEO James G.
Robinson to Lohan was leaked online on The Smoking Gun; in it, Robinson
criticized Lohan's heavy partying and lateness on set.
Georgia Rule was widely panned by critics, but the lead cast (Fonda,
Lohan and Huffman) was praised for their performances.
Having grossed $25 million against a budget of $20 million,
the film is considered a box-office bomb.
The film explores themes of small town, sexual abuse, parent child
relationship, grandparent grandchild relationship, veterinarian.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.